{
    "id": "ea0c277e47474ad7b06794c8618e9c46",
    "title": "Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He did not allow me ……………………….",
            "description": "We use a to-infinitive after allow.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "to go",
                "to going"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The injured woman ………………………….. to hospital.",
            "description": "We need a passive verb form here because the subject is not the doer of the action. ",
            "answers": [
                "took",
                "had taken",
                "was taken"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………………… anything from them yet.",
            "description": "The present perfect is more common with the time expressions already and yet.",
            "answers": [
                "did not hear",
                "have not heard",
                "had not heard"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The chief guest ………………………………… arrived.",
            "description": "The present perfect is more common with the time expressions already and yet.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "has",
                "will"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "‘Let me ………………………….,’ the boy cried.",
            "description": "We use an infinitive without to after let.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "to go",
                "going"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The birds …………………………….. when I woke up this morning.",
            "description": "We use the past continuous to talk about an action or situation that was going on a particular point of time in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "are chirping",
                "were chirping",
                "have been chirping"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I heard them ……………………………..",
            "description": "We use a gerund or an infinitive without to after the verbs see and hear.",
            "answers": [
                "talk",
                "to talk",
                "talking"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I saw him …………………………….. the road.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "cross",
                "to cross",
                "to crossing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Yesterday I …………………………….. an English movie.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to talk about finished past events.",
            "answers": [
                "watched",
                "have watched",
                "had watched"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The constable asked me what …………………………….. doing there.",
            "description": "The subject goes before the verb in an indirect question. ",
            "answers": [
                "was I",
                "I was"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………………. like to get up early in the morning.",
            "description": "\r\nWe use the simple present to talk about our likes and dislikes.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "not",
                "does not",
                "do not"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Ever since I ………………………….. my native place I ………………………………. here.",
            "description": "We use the simple past for finished actions or situations in the past. We use the present perfect continuous to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "left, have been living",
                "had left, had been living",
                "left, was living"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}